Email: travgottwaldt@gmail.com

LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/travisgottwaldt</u>

Summary

I competed in the Collegiate Cyber Defense Competition for 2 years as a firewall administrator on Palo Alto firewalls, we finished 3rd place in the state in 2023 and 1st place in 2024. As a firewall administrator, I gained practical experience in implementing port/application based security policies to protect against potential threats. I have experience in Security Operations Center environments, gained through labs on letsdefend.io, where I utilized SIEM tools to investigate cases. I have basic skills in Active Directory management, including user and group administration, permissions management, and domain controller setup. I've assisted with diagnosing computer issues, documenting production using Microsoft excel, and logging machine maintenance records. I'm familiar with a variety of operating systems, spanning from Windows Server 2019, Kali Linux, and Mac OS.

Skills

- Firewall Administration
- Palo Alto
- SIEM (Security Information and Event Management)
- Linux
- VMware
- Nmap
- Wireshark
- Python
- HTML
- Active Directory

Certifications

CompTIA A+

Awards

- 2024 Midwest Regional Collegiate Cyber Defense Competition 5th Place
- 2024 Minnesota Collegiate Cyber Defense Competition 1st Place
- 2023 Minnesota Collegiate Cyber Defense Competition 3rd Place

Work Experience

Collegiate Cyber Defense Competition

Firewall Administrator

November 2022 to Present

- Responsible for firewall configuration with multiple subnets.
- Implemented port/application based security policies for each zone.
- Monitored traffic logs for suspicious activity.
- Documented firewall configurations, policies, and procedures for reference.

Federal Cartridge - Anoka, MN Mechanical Adjuster September 2020 to March 2021

- Documented any maintenance requirements on machines throughout the department.
- Set up packing machines for shotgun shells.
- Tracked deadlines for each job and planned work orders accordingly.
- Conducted final inspections of shotgun shells before shipment.

Education

A.A.S in Cyber Security
Pine Technical and Community College, Pine City MN August 2022 – May 2024

CNC Machinist Diploma Anoka Technical College, Anoka MN January 2016 - January 2017